<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- TCS_Jerusalem_BaldwinIV_Text -->
<!-- Author: thecrazyscotsman -->
<!-- DateCreated: 9/3/2017 2:11:17 PM -->
<GameData>
	<LocalizedText>
		<!--LEADER INFO-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>보두앵 4세</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>보두앵 왕이시여, 성스러운 이 땅이 당신의 보호를 부르짖습니다! 이방의 침략자들이 당신의 왕국을 사방으로 포위했으나, 기독교도들의 대변자인 당신은모든 이들을 구원할 으뜸가는 희망입니다. 성묘소의 영원할 신성함은 왕께 달렸나니, 이제 최후의 과업을 위하여 최후의 힘까지 끌어모으십시오. 당신의 군령이 십자군의 기사들을 당신의 뒤로 집결시킬 것입니다. 이제 우리 주님의 이름으로 인하여, 예루살렘은 새롭게 다시 세워질 것입니다!</Text>
		</Replace>

		<!--CIVILOPEDIA-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_TITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>보두앵 4세</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_SUBTITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>예루살렘의 왕, 왕국의 수호자, 그리고 기사단의 후원자</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_QUOTE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>언젠가 자네가 하나님 앞에 서야 할 때가 된다면, "다른 누군가가 시켜서 그랬다, 그때는 그럴 수 밖에 없었다" 라고 말할 수는 없다는 말이야. 그건 참 의미없는 일이지. 그걸 꼭 기억하게.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Baldwin IV (1161 – 16 March 1185), called the Leper, or The Leper King reigned as King of Jerusalem from 1174 until his death. He was the son of Amalric I of Jerusalem and his first wife, Agnes of Courtenay.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Baldwin spent his youth in his father's court in Jerusalem, having little contact with his mother, Agnes of Courtenay, Countess of Jaffa and Ascalon, and later Lady of Sidon, whom his father had been forced to divorce. Baldwin IV was educated by the historian William of Tyre (later Archbishop of Tyre and Chancellor of the kingdom), who made a disturbing discovery about the prince: he and his friends were playing one day, attempting to injure each other by driving their fingernails into each other's arms, but Baldwin felt no pain. William immediately recognized this as a sign of serious illness, but it was not conclusively identified as leprosy until a few years later; the onset of puberty accelerated his disease, in its most serious lepromatous form.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Baldwin's father died in 1174 and the boy was crowned at the age of 13, on 15 July that year. In his minority the kingdom was ruled by two successive regents, first Miles of Plancy, though unofficially, and then Raymond III of Tripoli, his father's cousin. In 1175, Raymond III, the acting king of Jerusalem, made a treaty with Saladin. </Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4" Language="en_US">
			<Text>As a leper, Baldwin was not expected to reign long or produce an heir, and courtiers and lords positioned themselves for influence over Baldwin's heirs, his sister Sibylla and his half-sister Isabella. Sibylla was being raised by her great-aunt Ioveta in the convent of Bethany, while Isabella was at the court of her mother, the dowager queen Maria Comnena, in Nablus.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Raymond's regency ended on the second anniversary of Baldwin's coronation: the young king was now of age. He did not ratify Raymond's treaty with Saladin, but instead, at the young age of 13, Baldwin successfully attacked Damascus in order to draw the Muslim Sultan Saladin away from Aleppo. In 1176 he was leading men in the front in similar attacks at Damascus and Andujar to repel Muslim attacks. Baldwin also planned an attack on Saladin's power-base in Egypt. He sent Raynald of Châtillon (the former prince of Antioch through marriage to Amalric I's cousin Constance of Antioch) to Constantinople as envoy to Manuel I Comnenus, to obtain Byzantine naval support. Raynald had recently been released from captivity in Aleppo: Manuel paid his ransom, since he was the stepfather of the Empress Maria of Antioch. Manuel sought the restoration of the Orthodox patriarchate in the kingdom, and arranged the marriage of Bohemond III of Antioch to his great-niece Theodora Comnena, sister of the queen-dowager Maria. Reynald returned early in 1177, and was rewarded with marriage to Stephanie of Milly, a widowed heiress. This made him lord of Kerak and Oultrejourdain. Baldwin tried to ensure that Reynald and William of Montferrat co-operated on the defence of the South. However, in June, William died at Ascalon after several weeks' illness, leaving the widowed Sibylla pregnant with the future Baldwin V.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In November, Baldwin and Raynald of Châtillon defeated Saladin with the help of the Knights Templar at the celebrated Battle of Montgisard. That same year, Baldwin allowed his stepmother the dowager-queen to marry Balian of Ibelin, a conciliatory move to both, but it carried risks, given the Ibelins' ambitions. With Maria's patronage, the Ibelins tried to have the princesses Sibylla and Isabella married into their family as well.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In 1179, the king met with some military setbacks in the north. On 10 April, he led a cattle-raid on Banias, but was surprised by Saladin's nephew Farrukh Shah. Baldwin's horse bolted, and in saving him, the much-respected constable of the kingdom Humphrey II of Toron, was mortally wounded. On 10 June, in response to cavalry raids near Sidon, Baldwin took a force, with Raymond of Tripoli and the Grand Master of the Templars, Odo of St Amand, to Marj Uyun. They defeated the raiders fording the Litani River, but were caught by Saladin's main force. The king (unable to remount unaided) was unhorsed, and had to be carried off the field on the back of another knight as his guard cut their way out. </Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In the summer of 1180, Baldwin IV married Sibylla to Guy of Lusignan, brother of the constable Amalric of Lusignan. Earlier historians claimed that Sibylla's second marriage was entirely due to the influence of the King's mother; however, Hamilton argues that this is to reflect uncritically the personal grievances of William of Tyre and of the Ibelins. A plan to marry Sibylla to Hugh III of Burgundy had broken down; Raymond of Tripoli seems to have been attempting to marry her to Baldwin of Ibelin to bolster his power-base. A foreign match was essential to the kingdom, bringing the possibility of external aid. With the new French king Philip II a minor, Guy's status as a vassal of the King's cousin Henry II of England – who owed the Pope a penitential pilgrimage – was useful in this respect. Baldwin also betrothed his 8-year-old half-sister Isabella to Humphrey IV of Toron, repaying a debt of honour to Humphrey's grandfather, who had given his life for him at Banias, and removing Isabella from the control of her mother and the Ibelin faction (her betrothed was Raynald of Châtillon's stepson).</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Guy had previously allied himself with Raynald, who was by now taking advantage of his position at Kerak to harass the trading caravans travelling between Egypt and Damascus. After Saladin retaliated for these attacks in the campaign and Battle of Belvoir Castle in 1182, Baldwin, now blind and unable to walk, appointed Guy regent of the kingdom. By June 1183 however, Saladin had captured Aleppo and completed his encirclement of Jerusalem.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Nevertheless, Baldwin had become offended by Guy's actions as regent. Guy attended the wedding festivities for Isabella (now about 11) and Humphrey, held in Karak; however, the festivities were interrupted by Saladin, who besieged the fortress with the wedding guests inside. Baldwin marshalled what strength he had and lifted the siege, but Guy refused to fight Saladin and Saladin's troops managed to escape. Baldwin could not tolerate this and deposed Guy as regent. In disgrace, Guy retired to Ascalon, taking his wife the princess Sibylla with him. Although Baldwin was almost beyond his prime, due to his victories in Belvoir castle, Beirut and at Kerak castle, Saladin's campaigns in the Holy Land were delayed until the remainder of Baldwin's reign.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_11" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Although Baldwin seems to have held no ill-will towards his sister, Baldwin appointed his 5-year-old nephew Baldwin of Montferrat as his heir and successor, with the support of Agnes and her husband Reginald of Sidon, Raymond, and many of the other barons, excluding Sibylla from the succession. Raymond was to act as guardian of the infant heir, and later as regent if Baldwin IV was to expire, but Baldwin IV himself would continue to rule. The child was crowned co-king as Baldwin V on November 20, 1183.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_12" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In the early months of 1184, Baldwin attempted to have the marriage between Sibylla and Guy annulled. This was foiled by their holding fast in Ascalon, Guy refusing to attend the annulment proceedings. The military expedition to relieve Karak and the dynastic struggle had weakened Baldwin considerably. He died in Jerusalem in spring 1185, a few months after the death of his mother Agnes in Acre late in 1184. Though often suffering from the effects of leprosy and ruling with regency governments, Baldwin was able to maintain himself as king for much longer than otherwise might have been expected. As had been decided, Baldwin V succeeded his uncle, with Raymond of Tripoli as regent.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Jerusalem is a military and religious powerhouse, and under Baldwin IV is particularly dangerous as he leads his Crusaders against your holy places.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Jerusalem wields in two fists religious and military power. Its Holy Sites help build its armies faster, and it can purchase its Crusaders and Chapter Commanderies with [ICON_Faith] Faith. They are ready to make friends with those who follow their Religion, and implacable foes to those who follow a different one. The large amount of [ICON_Faith] Faith they seek to generate will help them gain attract many Great People, and their ability to churn out armies quickly will make them a very dangerous enemy.</Text>
		</Replace>

		<!--TRAITS/AGENDAS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TCS_TRAIT_LEADER_CROSS_OF_MONTISGARDE_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>몽기사르의 십자가</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TCS_TRAIT_LEADER_CROSS_OF_MONTISGARDE_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>수도회 영지를 보유한 도시는 군사 유닛 훈련 시 [ICON_Production] 생산 비용의 25%를 [ICON_Faith] 신앙으로 돌려받습니다. 성지 특수지구에서 4타일 내의 군사 유닛이, 부상으로 인한 [ICON_Strength] 전투력 감소를 받지 않고 적 유닛 처치 시 체력을 25만큼 회복합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_TCS_AGENDA_LEPER_KING_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나병왕</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_TCS_AGENDA_LEPER_KING_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>같은 종교를 따르며, 친선 관계를 선언한 문명을 좋아합니다. 다른 종교를 세운 문명을 증오합니다.</Text>
		</Replace>

		<!--DIPLOMACY-->
		<!--First Meet-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나는 보두앵, 주님의 은총으로 인하여, 예루살렘의 왕이 그대에게 인사하오.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>자, 우리의 신성한 도시를 방문하여 백성의 평화를 기도하는게 어떻겠나.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나는 자네의 초대를 겸허히 받아들이겠네.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>이교도에 반하는 우리의 결의를 다지기 위하여 서로의 수도를 방문하지 않겠나?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Greetings-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>예루살렘이 그대를 어떻게 도울 수 있겠나?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Delegation-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나의 두 팔로 자네의 사절단을 환영하겠네. 이것은 분명 위대한 일의 기반이 될 것이야.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나는 그리하면 안되리라 생각하네.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>자네의 수도로 대표단을 파견했다네, 석류와 보리... 그리고 신성한 땅의 축복을 함께 보내뒀지.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Open Borders-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>이는 우리 국민들 사이의 유대를 강화할 걸세.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나는 스파이들이 국경을 넘나드는 것을 허용치 않을걸세.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>서로 국경을 개방해서 우리 공동의 적에게 대항해봅시다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Declare Friendship-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>이 유대감이 더 돈독해지도록 합시다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>예루살렘 왕국은 당신의 도움은 필요없소.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>우리의 우호를 세계에 알리는 것은 우리가 함께라는 것을 공표하는 겁니다. 저와 함께 하시겠습니까?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>우리가 더욱 긴밀히 그리고 함께 성장하길 바랍니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>이건 실망스럽군요!</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Alliance-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>우리는 야만인같은 적들에게 둘러쌓였습니다. 나와 함께 성지를 수호하시겠습니까?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Kudos & Warnings-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>당신은 미래를 위해 현명한 판단을 내렸습니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>감히 예루살렘의 수호자를 조롱하였는가?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>하느님의 도시에서는 언제나 당신을 환영합니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>조심하게, 하느님은 우리 편일세.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>우리가 무찌른 침략자의 명단이 너무 많은데, 당신도 그들 중 하나가 되고싶소? 아니면 현명한 판단으로 예루살렘의 국경에서 군대를 철수하시겠소?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Trade-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY}</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY}</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Denounce-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>심지어 이세벨도 당신에 비하면 성인이었소.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>당신은 신앙에서 너무 멀리 벗어났습니다. (공개비난)</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Declare War-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나는 통치기간동안 많은 어리석은 자들을 만났지만 당신만큼 어리석은 자는 없었소.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>나는 자네에게 쏟아진 하나님의 분노이네. 회개하라, 그러면 자네의 죽음은 빨라 질 것이니.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Make Peace-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>평화롭게 하는 자는 복이 있나니.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>구원을 구하지 않는 한 평화는 없습니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>충분한 피가 땅을 적셨소. 우리 사이의 분쟁은 치유하고 더 이상 생명을 희생하지 않도록 합시다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Defeat-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>하나님의 성지가 당신의 끔찍한 손에 더럽혀지는 것을 보고 나는 이미 죽었소.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_TCS_LEADER_BALDWIN_IV_ANY}</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Agenda-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_TCS_AGENDA_LEPER_KING_SAME_RELIGION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>보두앵은 당신이 같은 종교를 공유해서 기뻐합니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_TCS_AGENDA_LEPER_KING_RELIGIOUS_FRIEND" Language="en_US">
			<Text>보두앵은 당신이 당신의 충실한 형제들과 우정을 나누게 되어 기쁩니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_TCS_AGENDA_LEPER_KING_DIFFERENT_RELIGION_FOUNDER" Language="en_US">
			<Text>보두앵은 당신이 다른 종교를 창시한 것에 분노합니다.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_REASON_FROM_AI_LEADER_ANY_REASON_TCS_AGENDA_LEPER_KING_DIFFERENT_RELIGION_FOUNDER" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(당신은 다른 종교를 창시하였소.)</Text>
		</Replace>
		
		<!--RWF Support-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_CHIEFDOM_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>지도자</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_AUTOCRACY_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>독재자</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_OLIGARCHY_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>집정관</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_CLASSICAL_DEMOCRACY_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>연설자</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_MERCHANT_REPUBLIC_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>총독</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_MONARCHY_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>왕</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_NOBLE_REPUBLIC_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>지도자</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_LIBERAL_DEMOCRACY_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>왕</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_PEOPLES_REPUBLIC_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>사무총장</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_MILITARY_GUARDIANSHIP_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>사령관</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_GOVERNMENT_JFD_EMPIRE_LEADER_TITLE_TCS_BALDWIN_IV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>황제</Text>
		</Replace>
	</LocalizedText>
</GameData>
